there's one skill I've found working
with voiceover talent that can speed up
their jobs and auditions and make them
much more efficient in voiceovers now
this may be a bit controversial and it
may hurt some people's feelings but I'm
gonna give it to you straight to
succeeded voice overs you need to be
able to read hello I'm William Williams
from Aliso creeks voiceover classes
whenever I talked to a new voice-over
talent they tell me two things I can
read and I can talk so I got this and
the first thing we find out is they
can't read okay I don't mean they can't
read of course they can read but what I
do mean is they can't get through 30
seconds of copy without missing a word
or hesitating some of these talents say
they want to do audiobooks trust me if
you can't get through 30 seconds of
voiceover copy you're gonna have a great
deal of difficulty reading an entire
book the subject of reading is the third
rail in the world of Education it's
distinctly possible for a student to get
all the way through high school and not
be able to read in a continuous flowing
way and understand what they're reading
but I'm not gonna go there that's for
the world of Education to sort out I'm
just giving you my practical experience
from directing and coaching Talent for
over 20 years first of all let me point
out that reading and talking are not the
same thing when you're talking you get
to make up all the words and you put
your own inflection into each word to
get the meaning across and since you're
making up the words you're phrasing
automatically fits your breathing so if
you start to run out of air you can cut
the sentence short and breathe also the
words automatically flow from your ideas
we don't say anything to anyone unless
there's some motivation behind that
speech some reason to say something
so that's natural speech when you're
reading for example a narration
paragraph or a commercial copy these are
not your ideas it's not the vocabulary
that you would choose and it may not be
the phrasing that you would use so
adjusting your speech skills to written
copy it's actually a very tricky process
in another video I talked about your
speech nonverbal toolkit these are the
nonverbal things you do when you speak
such as talking louder or softer raising
or lowering the pitch of your voice
putting certain emotions in your read
and so forth when you're reading someone
else's writing your mind has to
calculate how to include all these
variations of your voice you also have
to figure out where you're going to
breathe actually what you're doing is
taking speech that has been condensed
down to a piece of paper and Riaan
flayman communication and that can be
tricky here's the second challenge
actually our eyes were not made to read
our eyes were made to scan the savannahs
of Africa for any movements that may
help or hinder us so in life our eyes
don't move in a linear direction they
bounce around looking for things that
are changing so if you're on a grassy
plane in Africa and that grass over
there starts to move that usually means
there's something there that you can eat
or something there that might eat you
think about driving down the highway if
all the cars are going exactly the same
speed in their lanes it's almost like
they disappear then one of the cars
decides to get off the highway and you
notice their blinker and the fact that
the car is changing lanes so that's how
our eyes work in the real world
okay back to reading now in reading
you're asking for my eyes to move from
left to right until the end of the line
and then back to the left again and
to the right again for the new line so
reading asks your eyes to follow a very
linear path that is not natural there
are also different types of reading
sometimes we read for form and sometimes
we read for content when you first learn
to read you strictly read for form C spa
run run spot run but very quickly in
your education you begin reading for
content if you're reading them out in
the polian at the Battle of Waterloo you
really don't care exactly what the words
are you just want to find out what
happened on that fateful day most of the
reading we do in our daily lives
involves reading for content if you read
a magazine you're reading it for the
information not the way the words and
sentences are formed but if you're
reading commercial copy you need to read
all the words exactly as they're written
you can't just vaguely get the idea what
the sentences are saying and make up
your own words to describe it you have
to read the words verbatim which is a
skill you haven't practiced in years
oh and finally most of the time we read
to ourselves and we read to ourselves
two or three times faster than when we
read out loud maybe this is happening to
you you'll be reading through some copy
and then suddenly you realize that what
your mouth is saying and what your eyes
are reading are not in sync your eyes
have moved forward and are three or four
lines down the paragraph and your mouth
is still along the first line you can
tell this is happening if you get lost
in the copy or if you insert words into
the sentence that are in fact on the
next line or several lines down okay now
we've defined some of the reading
problems here are some solutions first
you have to get your eyes and your mouth
to synchronize remember in the second
grade when your teacher said don't
follow along with your finger
and don't move your lips when you read
well here's what I want you to do I want
you to follow along with your finger and
move your lips when you read by tracking
along with what you're reading with your
finger you force your eyes to slow down
and stay in the moment with a copy as
you're reading by the way don't actually
touch the paper or screen because the
mic might pick up that tiny noise
another technique that can help is to
use some kind of straightedge like a
ruler and only try to read one line of
copy at a time this prevents your eyes
from bouncing forward and picking up
stray words farther down in the copy
which happens quite frequently I have
another rule I use with my students and
I think it's very important and that is
when you're reading copy and you make a
mistake don't go back and correct your
mistake I have found that if when you
stumble you stop and go back and fix
those words that in fact you're giving
yourself permission to fail and by the
way you're also reversing the direction
your eyes are going in so your eyes will
tend to bounce around once again so if
you make a mistake ignore it and keep
reading trust me your mind already knows
you made the mistake and the next time
you read the copy it will correct the
mistake you want to push yourself
farther and farther through the copy to
the point where you can read 30 or 60
seconds or more without a mistake
but this requires practice to develop
the skill don't practice failing
practice succeeding if you can get to
the point where you can read a 30 second
audition without hesitating or stumbling
then guess what it will only take you 30
seconds to do a 30 second audition
auditioning is competitive and you often
need to do many auditions to get a job
improving your reading skills and
accuracy will make performing auditions
and jobs much more efficient if you
liked this video please subscribe to my
channel
and hit the like button and hit the bell
to be notified when new videos come out
and for more information on all things
voiceover visit Aliso Creek dotnet I'm
William Williams reminding you keep
talking
[Music]
you